

SENIOR / LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### **Details**

Berlin

Germany

sergii.vorobei1@gmail.com

#### Links

Linkedin

Website

#### Languages

English

German

Ukrainian

#### Skills

JavaScript, Typescript

Node.js

Python

React

Express, Nest.js

Flask, FastAPI, Django

DB

Docker, Kubernetes

CI/CD

Golang, Ruby, Java

### Hobbies

Cooking Running Traveling

#### **Profile**

Software / Lead Engineer with more than 10 years of experience in Software Development. Obtained Master's degree in Technical Automation science. I do my best in being a highly responsible and well-organized team member with leadership skills and a strong obligation for prioritizing deadlines. I possess 2 years of tech/team leading experience, knowledge of multi-paradigm programming concepts and approaches, application design and structure, managing code quality, and technical decisions.

# **Employment History**

#### Senior Full Stack / Tech Lead Engineer, Vantis, Berlin

MAY 2021 - PRESENT

Development of scalable solutions for people with cardiovascular diseases. Creating mobile applications involving smart device integration (fitness trackers, blood pressure measurement devices) and accompanying Backend infrastructure. Tasks prioritization and tech team management.

React, React Native, Node.js, Python, Django, Gatsby, PostgreSQL, Pandas, Numpy

#### Full Stack / Tech Lead Developer, Yara International, Berlin

NOVEMBER 2017 - MAY 2021

Digital farming applications and microservices development. Corrosion reduction, Nitrogen fertilizers optimization solutions. Leading mobile development team, usage of modern technologies, agile approaches, and best code delivery practices. Customers research conduction, iOS, and Android mobile apps implementation. Team members mentoring and onboarding.

React, React Native, Redux, Node.js, GraphQL, GraphQL, Golang, Java, AWS, Kubernetes

#### Senior Software Developer, SoftServe, Kyiv

JANUARY 2015 - OCTOBER 2017

Secure enterprise chat messenger and addons development. Implementing Web and Desktop applications. Working on technology stack selection, performance optimizations, CI configuration, automation test running, and deployment processes to Heroku and AWS. Pair programming, code review processes involvement. Organization and conducting technical company and project interviews.

Python, Flask, Django, React, Redux, Node.js, PostgresSQL, AWS

#### Middle Software Engineer, EPAM Systems, Kyiv

FEBRUARY 2015 - SEPTEMBER 2015

Development of a universal eCommerce mobile app based on Cordova PhoneGap for various platforms (Android, IOS, Blackberry OS) and screens (portrait, landscape) including a mobile site for one of the Canadian retailers. Discussing and implementing the new functionality, increasing testing coverage, and code analysis tools usage.

HTML5, CSS3, Phonegape, Vanilla Javascript, Angular, es6, Node.js, Express, MongoDB

## Web developer, QAP Creative, Zhytomyr

SEPTEMBER 2012 - FEBRUARY 2015

I was involved in Software architecture planning harnessing MVC oriented approach. Also took part in platform development based on Node.js, powered by Express framework, including CLI tool for synchronization with the framework. Besides, I taught HTML5/JavaScript courses at the company and city university.

HTML5, CSS3, Vanilla Javascript, Node.js, Knockout.js, Coffescript, Ruby, Rails

# **Education**

Master's degree Automation Engineer Technology, Zhytomyr State Technoligical University

JANUARY 2007 - DECEMBER 2012

# **Certifications**

MCPS: Microsoft Certified Professional

AUGUST 2016

MS: Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3

AUGUST 2016